Toggle Navigation

Toggle Navigation

Privacy Policy
==============

YOUR PRIVACY IS OUR PRIORITY
----------------------------

Built on world-class web services, we take your privacy seriously.  
_Effective August 28, 2023._

* * *

##### Summary

> We respect your privacy, value your trust, and take data collection seriously. We will not disclose your emails or private information to third parties for private gains. Beyond essential services, we use advanced tools like AI processing to enhance your user experience. We collect aggregate data such as favorite color choices, geographic locations, or usage data, both for features like Cloud Sync and for the AI-enhanced services we offer. Rest assured, you can opt out of AI processing anytime via your account settings. We aim to protect your data to the best of our ability, and will promptly and permanently remove any information you no longer want shared upon request.

##### Privacy Policy

Appfluence values your right to control what information you do or do not want others to see. As technology advances and our services evolve, we incorporate tools, like AI processing, to enhance user experience while preserving your privacy. By using Appfluence, you certify that you have read, understand, and agree with the provisions of our privacy policy.  

##### Artificial Intelligence (AI) Processing

Appfluence utilizes Artificial Intelligence, specifically OpenAI’s services, directly or via Azure, to process some requests. Examples of AI functions include:

* Generating a project with tasks toward a user-defined goal.
* Expanding on a partially described task and suggesting subtasks.
* Suggesting use cases for Priority Matrix based on a user’s job title and industry.

Users have the option to opt out of AI processing via their account settings page.

##### Information Appfluence Collects

Appfluence collects the following types of information, some of which is considered personal:

1. **Aggregate data** that is not personally identifiable for marketing and/or product enhancement. This may be shared with a third party.
2. **Project information** that is synchronized to our servers, where it is stored to provide backup and sync services for a given user account. We do not share this information with anyone outside Appfluence.
3. **Device id, IP and email address**, for the purpose of differentiating user accounts. This information is never given to a third party.
4. **Email address**, in order to message our users about task assignments, deadlines and other important notifications from the system, system invoices, and if the user has enabled the option, training sessions and other information about our products. This information is never given to a third party without consent.

##### How we use information we collect

How we use the information we collect depends on multiple factors, such as the type of involvement with our system, the hardware and software platforms you utilize, your subscription level and your communication preferences. Below are the specific ways in which we use this information:

* To offer our services: In order to carry on the performance of our contract with our users, we use your email as the unique ID that tells you apart from any other users in our system, determining the data elements every user is able to access. We may use your email address and the domain associated with it to infer your affiliation with a particular organization or industry, in order to personalize your experience with logos, avatars and preconfigured experiences based on imported metadata from third party platforms. We use data you explicitly or implicitly upload to our system in order to provide our task, project and priority management solution to you and your organization. We also use your explicit and implicit relationships with other users in our system to send real time notifications, allow task delegations, etc.
* To communicate with our users about our services: With your given consent to the processing of data in our system, when we have something useful to tell our users, we use their email address, account properties, and communication preferences to determine who can receive our messages. You can always opt out via your emailing preferences form in our system.
* For research and development: We use metadata that we collect during normal use of our applications for the successful performance of our contract with users, in order to learn how to improve the experience of our users, determine usage patterns to allocate resources, and to identify trends that inform our future product development.
* To market and promote our products: With your given consent to the processing of data in our system, we use your email address, metadata and communications preferences to send you messages regarding existing or future products that we determine might be of your interest. You can always opt out via your emailing preferences form in our system.
* For customer support: In order to provide a timely answer to your doubts and problems to protect the vital interests of our users, we review usage data from your account to quickly identify the issue you may be facing and the best course of action to resolve it.
* To protect our legitimate business interest and legal rights: Whenever asked by the relevant authorities for access to our customers data for compliance with a legal obligation (e.g. in order to carry a security audit or in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and audit functions), we will comply while preserving our users’ privacy within our reasonable means.
* For AI-Enhanced Services: We use data you provide to run AI processes that can generate projects, expand tasks, and offer suggestions tailored to specific job titles and industries. This data is processed using OpenAI’s services, either directly or through Microsoft Azure. You have the option to opt out of these AI-enhanced services via your account settings.

##### Data Access, Retention and Deletion

Users can access all their data, and export a machine-readable bundle file using our account management console. We will promptly honor requests to delete all data on any user, complying as soon as possible, but in any case within one month since your request. Simply contact our privacy address listed below and we will be happy to assist.

We store user data in data centers provided and managed by Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure. Unless otherwise stated, all our data resides in data centers inside the United States. Data is secured both in transit and at rest by industry standard encryption algorithms. More details are available upon qualified inquiries.

Appfluence also interfaces with OpenAI through its own platform or Azure for AI processing. Data used for AI processing is managed in accordance with OpenAI’s and Microsoft Azure’s respective privacy policies. Their stated commitment is that they will not use customer data to train their models, but we do not have direct visibility over this process.

Appfluence retains user data for the duration of an account’s active lifetime. User data will be deleted upon request by the account owner, or after seven years without account activity, following sufficient notice to the user via email, in order to facilitate reactivation or data exporting if necessary.

##### What are your data protection rights?

Appfluence would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:

**The right to be informed**: You have the right to learn if your data is used for purposes other than originally agreed. In this notice, and in our GDPR portal (https://appfluence.com/gdpr/), we describe the ways in which you can exercise this right.  
**The right to access**: You have the right to request Appfluence for copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.  
**The right to rectification**: You have the right to request that Appfluence correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request Appfluence to complete the information you believe is incomplete.  
**The right to erasure** You have the right to request that Appfluence erase your personal data, under certain conditions.  
**The right to restrict processing**: You have the right to request that Appfluence restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.  
**The right to object to processing**: You have the right to object to Appfluence’s processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.  
**The right to data portability**: You have the right to request that Appfluence transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.  
**The right to avoid automatic decision-making**: You have the right to request that Appfluence does not use your personal information to create profiles for automatic decision-making.  
**The right to AI Transparency**: Users have the right to understand how AI is used in processing their data and can opt out of AI processing via their account settings page.

##### Opinion Sharing

By emailing us, you allow us to share any positive reviews, comments, and enthusiasm to others.  

##### Eligibility

Appfluence does not knowingly solicit or collect information from children under the age of 16. If you are under the age of 16, do not register with Appfluence. If we learn that a user has registered in violation of this policy and we have collected information for a child under 16, or if we learn that a user between the age of 16 and 18 has registered without parental consent, we will delete this information as quickly as possible.  

##### Changes to Policy

In the event that Appfluence changes its privacy policy, we will notify our users by email message, or inside our apps in a prominent location. This Privacy Policy was last updated on August 28, 2023.  

##### Missing Information

If we have inadvertently failed to address certain privacy policies, please notify us and we will resolve it as soon as possible.  

##### Questions about Privacy

If you have questions about our privacy policy, contact us at [support+privacy@appfluence.com](mailto:support+privacy@appfluence.com). We are fully [GDPR compliant](https://appfluence.com/gdpr) and offer a series of self-serve mechanisms for users to access their data. Our Data Protection Officer is Pablo Diaz-Gutierrez. Written inquiries can be sent to:  
Appfluence Inc  
PO Box 8795  
Emeryville CA 94662  
USA  

Copyright © 2024 Appfluence Inc. All Rights Reserved.  
All other trademarks are owned by their respective owners. [Terms of use and EULA](https://appfluence.com/eula) | [Privacy](https://appfluence.com/privacy)
